

536 s graham st, pittsburgh, pa, 15232 kaizh.design@gmail.com [usa] +1 413-552-8424; [chn] +86 18658218125 www.k-zhang.com

PROFILE

Graduating fifth-year architecture student seeks architecture internship position utilize sound training and experience in architecture and urban design practice, creating innovative and practical solutions for various design challenges as essential goals for the post-graduate pursuit in the industry.

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, B.Arch, HCI Minor, Pittsburgh, PA, USA / 2015-2020

Harvard Graduate School of Design, Design Discovery - Urban Planning/Design, Cambridge, MA / 2019

The MacDuffie School, Honor Graduate, Granby, MA, USA / 2012-2015

Zhejiang Zhenhai High School, Ningbo, China / 2011-2012

PROFESSIONAL S K I L L S Digital: Rhinoceros + Grasshopper, V-Ray Rendering, Revit, QGIS,

Adobe suites (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects, XD, Lightroom, etc.),

3ds MAX, AutoCAD 2D/3D, SektchUp, InVision, Ecotect, Microsoft Office, etc.

Digital Fabrication: Industrial robotics, lasercut, CNC, 3D printing, etc.

Programming Language: Javascript, Python, RAPID

Analog: Casting, woodshop & construction, metal construction, vacuum forming, perspective drawing, freehand drawing, etc.

Language: English (full professional proficiency), Mandarin (native language)

EXPERIENCE

Instructor, Architecture Pre-college Program, Carnegie Mellon University / 2016-2017

Teaching Assistant, Intro to Architectural Robotics [48-555], Carnegie Mellon University / 2019

Architecture Intern, KTGY Architecture + Planning / 2017

Film Director, Feature Films: If You Are The One, CMU x UPitt / 2018-2019

Booth Chair [single-story structure construction], Spring Carnival, CMU / 2017-2019

Design Chair, Chinese Student Association, Carnegie Mellon University / 2016-2019

Design Director, Lunar New Year Extravaganza, Carnegie Mellon University / 2017-2019

Architecture Intern, Ningbo Architecture Institute / 2016

Design Intern, Joy Product Design / 2015

Primary PR Director & Designer, Run For Hope, The MacDuffie School / 2014 -2015

Choreographer, Main Dancer, Spring/Winter Concert, The MacDuffie School / 2012-2015

Team Design Lead, Destination Imagination® team, The MacDuffie School / 2014-2015

Chair of Design Committee, Zhejiang Zhenhai High School, 2011-2012

H O N O R S

College of Fine Arts - Dean's List [academic honor list], Carnegie Mellon University / 2016-2019

The Head's CIRCLE Awards of Creativity, The MacDuffie School / 2015

Golden Easel Award, The MacDuffie School / 2014 - 2015

Second Place, Western Massachusetts Mathematics League contest / 2014

Zhenhai High School Exam-exempted Admission, Zhenhai High School / 2012

First Class Scholarship, Jiaochuan Shuyuan / 2008-2011

2050 Megastructure: Pier 76, Manhattan, NY / 2018

- -Led a team of 3 for a large scale, semester-long theoretical project for an extremely high density development on the Hudson River in Midtown Manhattan
- -Designed and developed a 2750ft tall final building with over 10 million sf, anticipated for the year of 2050
- -Established the landmark on Hudson River, gateway of West Manhattan through ferry and metro transportation
- -Integrated significant features including highly sustainable ecological systems embedded, ready for clean power generation

John F. Kennedy International Airport, Terminal 4, Concourse A Expansion, Queens, NY / 2019

- -Designing the expansion of T4 at JFK parallel the real project currently being planned, a new structure of approximately 10 gates, 100ksf connected through the existing six-gate, 75ksf Concourse A to the main terminal.
- -Through the study of the duality of airport design paradigm and the global transportation and communication network, a complete design fully integrated to the existing context is created to explore the rich and varied conceptual design possibilities from macro to micro scale complexities.

Center of Integrated Neurology and Life Science, CMU, Pittsburgh, PA / 2019

- -Designing for the next generation campus academic laboratory that supports inter-disciplinary brain and behavioral researches between multiple CMU frontier territories, including neuroscience, psychology, computer science, statistics, and engineering
- -Receiving professorial advisories from Payette[Boston] Principal, Charles Klee, and practical requirements and demands from clients of Mellon Institute of Science
- -Landing the project as an extension/completion of the current Tepper Quad [CMU School of Business building]

AquaX, Urban Eco-morphology, Pittsburgh, PA / 2017

- -Led a team of 2 for a 30-acre urban residential complex development using parametric logic
- -Integrated multi-functional community portals [theater, amenity center, retails, etc.]
- -Introduced Eco-machines dealing with environmental emerging environmental issues

Nebula, Hangzhou, China / 2018

- -Led a team of 4 for a customized central urban co-living cluster with over 1000 residential units and office complex
- -Developed using parametric aggregation strategy for residential business unit deployment

Environmental Charter School [ECS], Pittsburgh, PA / 2018

- -Designed for a real local high school expansion proposal for the owners of the existing ECS
- -Set the anchor point for lower-income diversified community
- -Presented with nature-friendly interior environment and habitable outdoor educational space

Na'tian Pavilion, Suqian, China / 2017

- -Led a team of 4 for a resort pavilion proposal of national forest park Na'tian Hua Hai
- -Designed for serving as the destination for tourist traffics and stimulator of local economy
- -Integrated exhibition, dining, shopping center, and amenity facilities

Hoop House [built], Pittsburgh, PA / 2016

- -Led a team of 6 to build a portable lightweight aluminum-plastic enclosure for extending the garden season of raised garden beds
- -Permanent installation on the roof level of David L. Lawrence Convention Center

Booth [built], Pittsburgh, PA / 2017-2020

- -Co-led a crew of over 60 people from Chinese Student Association to build a one story wood structure construction during CMU Spring Carnivals
- -Built two award winning constructions [2017-2018], one currently under design phase [2020]
- -Designed primary structure and interior planning
- -Included interactive games and elaborate decorations to showcase Chinese culture

^{*}Projects details available on website/portfolio